(tense music)
(wind blowing)
(gentle music)
(person groaning)
- Journal of Reverend
Edmond Fuller,
month of November in the
year of our Lord, 1621.
It seems like a lifetime
ago that Abigail
and I first arrived
in the new world,
stumbling off the boat
alongside 100 other souls
with little more than
the clothes on our backs
and our hopes for the future,
hopes that were dashed
when the Reverend
Peters and I disagreed
over where to build
our community's chapel.
The trouble spiraled from
there until it was clear
the two of us weren't
ever going to get along.
So it was that I
convinced Abigail
it was time we struck
out on our own,
knowing that with God's
grace, my two hands
and sack of tools,
I could build a home
and chapel for ourselves.
That was in the spring,
many a month ago.
And now here we are in winter,
holed up in a tiny cabin
with no warmth and
not a thing to eat.
(person groaning)
Poor Abigail is ailing.
She's not long for this world
and I cannot be far behind her.
I've never known such
a feeling of hunger.
My fear is that at any moment,
a madness may take hold of me.
(person groaning)
(tense music)
For what I'm about to receive,
may the Lord make
me truly thankful.
(tense music)
(person screaming)
(person groaning)
(dramatic music)
(object whirring)
(thunder crashing)
"And God said to Adam, the flesh
that is torn from a living beast
at the time that
its life is in it
before all its
breath has gone out,
thou shall not eat nor its
blood shall thee drink.
Those that disobey this command
shall never enter
the kingdom of heaven
or find their rest
in the earth."
(dramatic music)
(wind blowing)
This will be the final
entry in this journal.
I, Reverend Edmund
Fuller, hereby confess
to having committed
a most terrible sin.
The sentence for such
a crime is execution.
(object creaking)
Being that I am alone here,
I'm forced to carry out
this sentence by my own hand
and it must be done quickly,
for I fear the hunger that
drove me to such terrible acts
is rising within me once again.
May the Lord forgive me
for what I have done.
(gun banging)
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
♪ Fire and the rain ♪
(phone buzzing)
♪ My love, I'll keep you safe ♪
- Arnie, just saw your
message, a happy Thanksgiving
to you too. The
cabin, it's fantastic.
It's even better
than the pictures.
I mean, come on a hot
tub and a steam room.
Oh, and thanks for throwing
in the limo ride out here.
Sara was very appreciative,
if you know what I mean.
I just gotta know, how
the hell did you get
a permit to build out here?
It's all protected
forest land, isn't it?
(birds chirping)
Trust you to find a way.
(gentle music)
Listen, Arnie, I can't
talk for too long.
Cyndy could be here at any
moment to drop off the kids.
That's what Thanksgiving's
all about, right?
Getting the family together.
No, Cyndy won't need
to stick around.
Thank God I mean,
can you imagine?
Listen, I gotta go.
Thanks again so much
for loaning the cabin.
Yeah, I'll see you in
the office Tuesday.
Okay, okay, bye, bye.
Andi, Noah, happy Thanksgiving.
What's that?
The new Stephen King?
- Christ, dad, only
boomers read Stephen King.
- Right.
(gentle music)
Why are you guys on foot?
Freeway's a good half mile away.
- We know that Tom,
we just walked it.
- What happened to the EV?
- Dead battery.
- Come on Cyndy.
- That battery is old, I told
you about it two months ago.
- That's what we have
auto insurance for.
Didn't you call them?
- Yes, I called them. You
took my name off the policy.
- I was gonna warn
you about that.
- Look, can you
just take me back
to town once the
kids are settled in?
- No, I don't have
a car out here.
- What?
- Don't worry.
I'll make some calls,
let's just head on inside.
You're not gonna
believe this place.
Six bedrooms, kitchen,
steam room, hot tub.
(gentle music)
Okay, through here.
(feet clopping)
- So this is Arnold's
little love nest.
- Vacation cabin for his family.
Actually, we're the
first to use it.
Construction only finished
a couple of months ago.
- Weren't you gonna
make some calls?
- Oh, okay.
Signal's better outside.
(person sighing)
(dramatic music)
(wood creaking)
(feet clopping)
- Listen, as much as
I hate to say this,
try to give your dad
a chance this weekend.
Spending Thanksgiving
with his family
always really
meant a lot to him.
- If family meant so much
then why did he leave?
- Come on Andi, you know
it's not that simple.
Adults have different needs.
- I'm almost 20 mom.
I'm not six, I am an adult.
- Well then perhaps you
could try acting like one.
- Hey, cool it mom.
- You're right, Andi, I'm sorry.
Today is just turning out
to be a really bad day.
(upbeat music)
- How about later this
afternoon, this evening?
I know it's Thanksgiving,
but this is an emergency.
All right, all
right, thanks anyway.
- In answer to your question,
your father and
I are breaking up
because the relationship
has run its course.
That's all. You can understand.
You broke up with Fisher.
- I went on like three
dates with Fisher.
I wouldn't call
that breaking up.
You and dad have been
together forever.
- And we raised a
beautiful family
that we are very proud of.
Yes, even you, Noah.
But now you kids are grown,
maybe it's time to
make some changes.
I know this is a
different situation
to what we've all been used to,
something we all have to
deal with in our own way.
But I think that if
you give it a chance.
- [SARA] Oh, I didn't realize
there was anyone here.
- So I can see.
(gentle music)
- Hey everyone, this is my,
this is Sara.
- Don't get up, I just
popped in to find my phone.
I think I left it on the couch.
- Noah, why don't you
move aside so Sara can.
- [SARA] Don't worry, found it.
- Your accent's cool,
are you British?
- That's right.
- Sara and I met
when I was in London,
on a layover at the airport.
- A layover, how appropriate.
Tom was kind enough to
help me with my bags.
- Sara, this is Andi and Noah.
- Pleased to meet you both.
- So how's it going with
getting the car towed?
- I called up the six closest
places, five didn't pick up.
And the one that
did is busy all day.
- Well, it's Thanksgiving,
what did you expect, Tom?
- Okay, I'll think of something.
- I don't think we've
been introduced.
- Right, this is Sara,
Sara, this is Cyndy, my.
- His wife.
- Separated of course.
- Still on good terms, I hope,
for the sake of your
lovely children.
- I think it's time I showed
you two to your rooms,
Andi, Noah, you
wanna come with me?
(upbeat music)
(tense music)
Through here.
(birds chirping)
What do you think?
- Oh.
(upbeat music)
- Look Noah,
I know we haven't had
much of a chance to talk
since your mom and I decided
to go our separate ways.
You don't exactly make it easy
listening to that
noise all the time.
Well look, that's why I wanted
to get us all together
for the holidays.
Spend a little quality time
with you and your sister.
- Family time, right?
- Yeah, that's it.
- Without mom.
- Okay, it's more of a chance
for you to get to know Sara.
So how's the band come along?
- The band?
- Yeah.
You, Mikey and that skinny
kid, what's his name?
- The band broke up.
- Oh, that's a pity.
- In July, it was
six months ago dad,
the skinny kid's name is Denver
and his dad actually
gave a shit,
so he used to come
and see us play.
- Hey, there's no need
for that kinda language.
You know I have to travel a
lot for work, it's my job.
I'm here now, son,
so why don't we try
and have a nice old
fashioned Thanksgiving
like we used to do when
you and Andi were kids.
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
(feet clopping)
- [SARA] Car trouble?
- Don't worry, I'm not
planning on staying.
- Oh, it's all right with
me, the more the merrier.
I'm told it's a beautiful
area, the forest around here.
- Didn't you see it
when you arrived?
- It was dark when we got here.
Tom and I haven't really
stepped outside since.
- I'll bet.
- I'm more of a city girl.
Not really one for
hiking in the forest.
- No, I imagine walking the
streets is more your thing.
- I'm sorry?
- I mean, you're not exactly
dressed for it, are you?
Although I can't imagine
anything you are dressed for.
- [SARA] Oh, I see.
Perhaps I ought to
go and get changed.
(feet clopping)
- He doesn't have
any money, you know.
(gentle music)
(hand knocking)
- So how's the room?
- Very pink.
- Yeah, it's my
buddy Arnold's cabin.
His daughter's a little
younger than you are.
So any more thoughts
about what you wanna do
after graduation?
- I don't know, maybe
study some more.
There's a couple grad schemes
that look interesting.
- So another few
years of reading books
before you get an actual job.
- What do you care?
- Well, your mother and I
can't support you forever, Andi.
- Oh, so you just want
me out of your hair?
- It's not what I meant.
- You left, dad, you moved out.
You don't even have to
see me and Noah anymore.
- Of course I wanna see you.
That's the whole
point of this weekend.
It's not about not
wanting to see you,
it's just that things may get
a little difficult financially
now that your mother and
I are no longer together.
You know, that means two houses,
two sets of cars, two
sets of everything.
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
(door whirring)
(feet clopping)
(gentle music)
- Not interrupting
anything am I?
Only, I think your
father wanted us all
to get to know one
another a little better.
And there's no time like
the present is there?
It's a lovely place this
cabin of your father's,
there's even a steam room.
Meant to be very
good for your skin.
I thought I might try it
out before I get dressed.
Just need to grab
myself a towel.
Maybe I'll see you
there? Five minutes.
- Kids all settled in?
- Yeah.
- So I'll just be
going then, shall I?
- I don't really
know what to say.
It doesn't look like we'll
be able to get the car towed
until after the holiday.
- So what are you suggesting?
- Well, it is Thanksgiving,
why don't you stay for dinner?
(person laughing)
- You have to be
kidding, are you serious?
- Well, there are
plenty of rooms
and I think the
kids would enjoy it
having the whole family around.
- And exactly what kind
of family is this Tom?
Mom, dad, and dad's
a new piece of ass.
- Shh, come on, don't
raise your voice.
- I will raise more than
my God damn voice Tom.
I mean, how could you do this
to me, humiliate me like that?
Or was that your plan all along?
- No, it wasn't my plan.
I just thought you
were gonna come here,
drop off the kids and
go back into town.
I didn't think you and
Sara would see each other.
- I bet you didn't.
You know the two of
you seem pretty cozy
for someone you only met
just a couple of weeks ago.
- What do you mean?
- I mean, her being here for
Thanksgiving to meet your kids
just seems like you're
moving pretty fast.
Unless of course.
- Unless what?
- Unless you've been
seeing her for a whole hell
of a lot longer than that.
Like maybe while you and
I were still together.
- No, of course not.
- 'Cause if I find
out that you have,
well that puts an
entirely different spin
on the divorce proceedings
now, doesn't it? Infidelity.
- Cyndy, there's no need
to get into all of this.
Come on, why don't you
just stay for dinner.
I'll make sure Sara stays
out of your hair until then.
And oh shit, I gotta go get
the turkey into the oven.
(door whirring)
(gentle music)
- Happy Thanksgiving.
(upbeat music)
(steam whirring)
- There you are, you're early.
I'm a great admirer
of punctuality.
Wait a minute, what
are you wearing?
- I didn't bring any swimwear.
- Swimwear, who needs swimwear?
If we were back home in Europe,
we'd both be completely naked.
- What?
- That's right, not a stitch on.
You just strip it all off
and nobody bats an eyelid.
- Sounds cool.
- Have you ever been
to Europe yourself?
- No, my dad travels a lot
that he ever takes us with him.
- Poor you, it seems so unfair
that your father gets to enjoy
so many things that you don't.
You know, I think
it's about time
things got a little more
steamy in here, don't you?
- Huh?
(dial whirring)
(person coughing)
Are you okay?
- I think I'd better
get back to my room
in case my dad comes
looking for me.
- Suit yourself.
(tense music)
- [REVEREND FULLER] God
said to Adam, the flesh
that is torn from
a living beast,
thou shall not eat.
Those that disobey this command
shall never enter
the kingdom of heaven
Or find their rest in the earth.
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
(floor creaking)
(tense music)
(door whirring)
- Noah, Andi, come on you
two, it's family time.
(door creaking)
(birds chirping)
(gentle music)
Come on.
Am I the only one who's
gonna make an effort here?
This is not what
the founding fathers
would've wanted
during Thanksgiving.
Staring at screens and books.
Anyway, kids, the good news
is that your mother might
be staying for dinner.
- What?
- Awkward.
- It will not be awkward.
We're all sensible adults
and there's plenty
of food to go around.
- Is your girlfriend cooking?
- No, Sara doesn't cook, I'll
be taking care of everything.
- That'll be interesting.
- Where is Sara anyway?
- She's spending some alone
time in the steam room.
So if anyone has
anything they wanna say
to clear the air,
now's the time.
Good, right, I'll
take that as a no.
So here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna put these all away.
And yours Cyndy, come on.
- You're taking my phone,
you're not serious.
- We have to set an
example for the kids.
I'm gonna put mine away as well.
- What if there's an emergency?
- The cabin has a regular
telephone right there.
There's a safe in
the master bedroom.
I'm gonna lock these away for
the rest of the afternoon.
(people groaning)
You'll get them back
right after dinner, okay?
Until then, I want us all
to actually be together.
You know, this may
be the last time
we actually get to do this.
- And whose fault is that, Tom?
- I'll be back in a second.
(feet clopping)
(tense music)
(person growling)
(object whirring)
(machine beeping)
- Well, this sucks.
- Why are you going
along with this mom?
- I guess I don't really
feel like I have much choice.
We're stuck here with no car.
And for all his faults,
I think your dad feels guilty
that he hasn't been
spending much time with you.
Maybe if you give him a chance.
- To do what?
Parade his stupid
girlfriend around
while we pretend
that this is normal.
- What's the point of
Thanksgiving anyway,
giving thanks for what?
I'll be back in my room.
(door banging)
- What's going on?
- We all agree this sucks,
I'll be in my room too.
(gentle music)
- Not you as well.
- I need some air.
(door banging)
(upbeat music)
(door creaking)
(steam whirring)
(upbeat music)
(person coughing)
(birds chirping)
(gentle music)
- Peaceful here, isn't it?
- Not the word I'd use.
- I meant out here, the forest.
- It's beautiful.
I'm surprised Arnold got a
permit to build out here.
- Well, you know, Arnie,
the smart guy, found a way.
- I used to think
you were a smart guy.
Now I'm not so sure.
- This isn't just some stupid
midlife crisis happening.
- Isn't it?
- It's been a long time
coming, you know that.
- All I know is that I'm
at home hauling laundry
for the fourth time in a week
when suddenly I'm
hearing on a phone call
that you don't
live there anymore,
on a phone call Tom.
- Thought it would
be better that way.
- Better? Better for who?
I mean, I guess if you
mean better in the sense
that you avoided having your
head put through the drywall,
well then yes, it was better.
- See, this is it, this
is why I had to leave.
- Wasn't serious
about the drywall.
- Yeah but you always just
keep blaming me for everything.
- Who else can I blame Tom?
- There are two people
in this marriage Cyndy.
Neither of us are perfect,
but at least I
don't pretend to be.
- I don't pretend to be perfect.
- Did you ever ask
yourself why a man
might want to give
up everything?
Leave his two kids,
his home of 20 years.
- I don't know maybe
'cause he's selfish?
- Because you drove me away.
(tense music)
(wood creaking)
See, this is it, the
famous silent treatment.
It's a form of abuse you
know, I looked it up.
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
- I am not trying
to be hurtful Tom,
it's just that sometimes
I can't understand
what the hell is wrong with you.
You were always in a bad mood,
always snapping at the kids.
- Do you ask yourself why?
Maybe it was because
you were always
snapping at me, criticizing me.
I never expected to
win man of the year.
But don't I get any credit
for being just a decent,
regular guy who works
hard at his job,
and does his best at home.
I know I'm away a lot,
but I meant what I
said on Thursday.
- So did I Tom.
You have no idea the
damage you've done.
(object clinking)
- [NOAH] Down here.
- Are you spying on me?
You little prick,
your own sister.
- [NOAH] No, I was
just exploring.
There's all these
tunnels down here,
like a crawl space
into the cabin.
Can you open the vent?
(vent whirring)
- What is this?
- I don't know.
But you like old books, right?
Thought you could check it out.
- Thanks, I will, it might
get me through this weekend.
It's really fucked up, right?
What's it like down there?
- Weird, I mean, it's
not what you'd expect.
Everything looks really old.
- You better not be
down there too long.
You know dad's gonna
want us all upstairs
for the big Thanksgiving dinner.
- Yeah, I know, I'm
just gonna go see
if I can find any
more cool old stuff.
Catch you later.
(vent creaking)
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
- I am not going to stop being
mad about how you did this
and I really can't
say how the kids
are going to respond
to this weekend.
- Same way they
respond to everything.
Noah will hide under
his headphones,
Andi will bury herself
in a book. Anyway,
they're not kids anymore,
Andi's at college.
Noah can take care of himself.
- They're still kids to me,
Tom and you've hurt them.
They might not show
it, but they are hurt.
- This is why I
wanted to do this.
You know how important
Thanksgiving is to me,
getting the family
together, the big dinner.
- Speaking of which, don't
you have food to prepare?
- Oh yeah.
Yeah you're right,
so much to do.
Hey, can you help me out?
- Help you out?
Making dinner while your
girlfriend relaxes in the sauna?
Go fuck yourself, Tom.
(gentle music)
(wood creaking)
(tense music)
(leaves crunching)
(dramatic music)
(person growling)
- [REVEREND FULLER] For
what I'm about to receive,
may the Lord make
me truly thankful.
(person grunting)
- Noah.
(tense music)
Listen, I know things
haven't exactly worked out
as I planned this weekend.
Well, this whole year, actually.
(flesh whirring)
Can you please at least do me
the courtesy of showing up?
(person growling)
30 minutes okay?
(gentle music)
(hand knocking)
- Come in.
- So,
how you doing kiddo?
I guess I haven't been much
of a dad these past few weeks.
I figured you guys just
didn't need me around anymore.
- Maybe you figured right.
- But if that were true,
there'd be no reason
for you to be upset would there?
- I'm not upset,
I just wish I knew
what was going on with
you guys, you and mom.
- It's kind of complicated.
- Complicated, that's
what people say
when they don't wanna
talk about something.
- Okay, so what exactly
do you want to know?
- Is it me or Noah?
- What do you mean?
- Did we make you wanna leave?
- Honey, I'm not
leaving you and Noah.
This is just about
your mother and I.
Come on, you're
not a kid anymore.
You've had boyfriends
at college, right?
You know how relationships are.
At first it's kind of fun,
but later it gets, you know,
it gets complicated.
I just needed some time
to uncomplicate
my life a little.
So look, I'm gonna go
start prepping dinner.
You wanna come and gimme a hand?
- Actually, I'd rather
have some more alone time.
- Okay, that's fine too.
- Just one more question.
- What is it?
- How old is this cabin?
- It's brand new,
my buddy Arnold
had it constructed
over the summer.
We're the first to use it.
- Yeah, that's what
I thought you said.
- Why do you ask?
- I was just wondering if
maybe a part of it could
be older or something.
- Oh, you mean the foundations?
- The what?
- Foundations
under the building.
Apparently there
was already a cabin
built here hundreds
of years ago.
It was more of a ruin really.
But because it was already
here, my buddy Arnold
was able to get a permit
to build on top of the
existing structure.
All he had to do was make
sure that what was left
of the existing foundations
were incorporated
into the new building.
Pretty smart, huh?
Anyway, I'll see you at dinner.
(gentle music)
- Oh, there you are,
what do you think?
This one or this one?
- Maybe something a
little more conservative.
- I don't do conservative Tom.
You know that.
- Maybe, maybe
everything's gonna be okay.
- And why wouldn't it be?
- Well, you've seen my kids.
It's not gonna be so
easy to win them over.
- Well, I don't know,
I'm sure I've got your
boy suitably intrigued.
- Andi's not gonna be so easy.
- We've only just met Tom.
Can take time to get
close to someone.
- I've been her father
for almost 20 years.
I'm not even sure how
close I am to her.
- Relax, Tom.
I can get anyone wrapped
around my little finger.
- How?
- I have my ways.
Do we have time for
a demonstration?
- Well, the kids
are in their rooms
and Cyndy's outside.
Can we make it fast?
- We can make it
anything you want.
We've barely scratched
the surface, you and I.
You wouldn't believe
how far I'll go.
(gentle music)
Wait a minute, where's my phone?
- Relax, I put it in the safe
with all the other cell phones.
- In the safe?
Are you expecting a robbery?
- No, it's just,
I don't want there
to be any other
distractions during dinner.
You know how kids are with
their cell phones these days.
- I'm not one of your kids Tom.
Can't I just check my messages?
- Okay.
(machine whirring)
- Just gimme a hand here,
this dinner's important to me.
I want it to be special.
- Fine. If it's so special,
you've probably got
more important things
to do than fooling
around in here.
- Yeah, maybe you're right.
- Oh, and when you get a chance
before this weekend's over,
we ought to talk finances.
- What?
- Oh, you know,
only for the basics.
- Okay, no problem. I'd
go for the second dress.
(gentle music)
(birds chirping)
(thunder crashing)
- [REVEREND FULLER] Journal
of Reverend Edmond Fuller
month of November in the
year of our Lord, 1621.
It seems like a lifetime
ago that Abigail
and I first arrived
in the New World,
stumbling off the boat
alongside 100 other souls
with little more than
the clothes on our backs
and our hopes for the future.
That was in the spring,
many a month ago.
Now here we are in winter.
Holed up in a tiny
cabin with no water
and not a thing to eat.
This will be the final
entry in this journal.
I, Reverend Edmund
Fuller hereby confess
to having committed
a most terrible sin.
(person screaming)
The sentence for such
a crime is execution.
May the Lord forgive me
for what I have done.
(thunder crashing)
(gentle music)
(rain pouring)
- Weather sounds ominous.
- Then it's a good
thing we're all safe
and warm in the cabin.
Nothing's gonna spoil
this dinner Cyndy.
- Good evening, Cyndy.
Looking forward to Tom's dinner?
- I'm sure it'll
be an experience.
Tom's never cooked
for me before.
- Well, that's something
we have in common.
- I'm perfectly capable
of making dinner.
- Are you okay honey?
- What Is it, something wrong?
- No, I guess it's the
weather, it freaks me out.
- You know she's sensitive Tom.
- Maybe you should take a break
from all those horror stories.
- Come sit by me honey.
- I was just about to
go bring the sides.
Hold tight everyone.
(liquid pouring)
- Anyone?
- I think I need
something stronger.
- How about you Andi?
- No, thank you,
she's too young.
- She's a grown woman.
- She is under 21,
which is legal drinking
age in this country.
- You're joking, 21?
- Can someone fetch Noah?
I don't want everything
to get cold while we're waiting.
- I'll go knock on his door.
- Here, get this down you
while your mother's
out of the room.
(gentle music)
- I've been at college
for like a year.
It's not exactly my
first time drinking.
- I'm sure. Another?
- I know what you're
trying to do Sara,
and it won't work with me.
- What exactly is it
that I'm trying to do?
- Get me on your side
so you can worm your
way into my family.
- Worm my way in?
- You might be able to charm
my dad, my stupid brother.
I mean, we all know a
man can't think further
than the end of his dick,
but I can think
of a million ways
to fuck up your little weekend.
- Perhaps you'd be kind enough
to keep your
thoughts to yourself.
(thunder crashing)
- Here we are mashed
potato, pear salad.
Is Noah coming?
- Knocked on his door
but he didn't answer.
I don't know what
to do with that boy.
- I know where he is.
I'll go get him.
(tense music)
(door creaking)
Noah?
- This all looks
marvelous Tom, well done.
- Looks like it was mostly
bought from the store.
- Thank you Sara.
And the turkey will go
right there in the center.
(knife whirring)
- So turkey, family.
It's basically just Christmas
without the gifts, right?
- What do you mean?
- Well, Thanksgiving, I mean
we don't have it in England,
so I basically have no
idea what you're all doing.
(tense music)
- Noah, where are you
you little asshole?
Dad's gonna go insane
if you miss dinner.
- It all started when the
first pilgrims came to America
and they gave thanks for a
safe crossing from Europe.
- No, that's the Mayflower.
- Yeah, I know that was
the name of the ship.
- Yeah, but that's not
what Thanksgiving is.
Thanksgiving started
when the first pilgrims
were freezing through the
winter and then they gave thanks
when the spring came.
- Yeah, that sounds right.
Warm weather brought
a big harvest.
It saved everybody and
they gave thanks for that.
- So then why is
Thanksgiving in November?
(tense music)
- Noah?
(leaves whirring)
- It doesn't matter
how it all started.
Point of Thanksgiving
is that all the families
get together and then.
- Give thanks.
- Right.
- But why?
- Good question.
- I think it's time I got
the turkey out of the oven.
- This I have to see.
(dramatic music)
- Ew gross,
Noah, I swear to
God when I find you.
(tense music)
- Can anyone suggest why
turkey might take longer
than the suggested cooking time?
- Well, how's it looking?
- Pretty raw.
- Raw, you've had it
in there for hours.
Did you switch the oven on?
- Of course I did,
not an idiot, Cyndy.
The outside looks fine,
it's just the inside.
- Well, how long have
you had it defrosting?
- What?
(wood creaking)
- Noah?
- I think we may have a problem.
- You didn't put a frozen
turkey straight into the oven?
- Christ Tom, even I know you
can't cook a frozen turkey.
- Noah?
(dramatic music)
(person screaming)
(person breathing)
(flesh whirring)
- [REVEREND FULLER] For
what I'm about to receive,
may the Lord make
me truly thankful.
(person breathing)
(person screaming)
- What the hell happened?
(person breathing)
(tense music)
(rain pouring)
- Oh my god, honey,
what happened?
- There's something down there.
- Down where?
- Under the cabin.
- There's some kind of hatch
in the floor in Noah's room.
- Noah was fooling
around down there.
So I went to get him.
- What's wrong with her leg?
- Oh my God, Tom.
- There's the first aid
kit in the kitchen. Sara.
- Right.
- Honey, what happened?
- I told you, there's
something down there.
It tried to grab me.
- What kind of thing?
- It was probably
just an animal.
- An animal did that to her leg?
- No, no, I got
it stuck on a nail
and it wasn't an animal.
- Give me that.
We need to call 911.
- Wait a second, why don't
we all just calm down
and think about
what happened here?
Andi went crawling
under the building,
got spooked out by an animal.
- It wasn't an animal.
- Well maybe it was just
Noah trying to freak you out.
In a panic to get out of there
you scratch your leg
on a nail, that's it.
- It wasn't Noah.
- Honey, it might have been.
You said yourself
he went down there.
- Let's not all get crazy,
call the cops and get your
little brother into trouble.
Why don't I just go down
there and take a look around?
- It is not safe down there.
That's the old part
of the building dad.
- The old part?
- What's she talking about Tom?
- It's the foundations.
There was an old cabin built
here before, an old ruin.
They kept part of
the old foundations
and put it into the new
building, that's it.
It was the only way
Arnie could get a permit
to build out here.
- Who's Arnie?
- Tom's work buddy, the
guy who owns this cabin.
- I thought you said
this was your cabin?
- I said it was mine to
use whenever I needed to.
I practically own it,
it's the same thing.
- No it isn't.
- I told you he
doesn't have any money.
- Can we talk about
this later Sara?
Lemme just deal with
this first, okay?
There's a flashlight
in the bedroom.
I'm gonna take it down
into the foundations.
Just stay here and
wait for me, okay?
- But Dad, what if
you don't come back?
- If I don't come back,
then you can call the cops.
There's a telephone right here.
(gentle music)
- What's got you so freaked out?
- There's this journal
I was reading. Noah,
he found it down in the
foundations, it's really old.
Like hundreds of years old.
- Honey, are you sure?
- Of course, it's right here.
- Noah?
- I swear I had
it in my hand mom.
- Is that it?
- Noah, are you down here?
- I read the whole
thing this afternoon.
It was a journal of
a Reverend Fuller.
He was the guy that
built the original cabin,
the one dad was talking about.
(wood creaking)
- Noah, listen, your
sister's been hurt.
We're all getting a little
tired of you fooling around.
If you come out right now,
maybe we can all enjoy
a Thanksgiving dinner.
What do you say?
- This Reverend,
I think he was one of
the original pilgrims.
He and his wife got kicked
out of their settlement
and he built a cabin
here in the woods.
(tense music)
- [CYNDY] What's in this
journal that's so disturbing.
- Here, the last part.
- Honey, I can't read
that, I need my glasses.
- It was winter,
they were starving.
Him and his wife.
- And then what happened?
(person screaming)
(flesh whirring)
(dramatic music)
- He ate her.
He killed her and he ate her.
It's all here in
his own handwriting.
- [TOM] Hey, down here.
- Tom.
- [TOM] There are
tunnels down here
that go all the way
around the cabin.
- Have you found Noah?
- [TOM] No.
- I don't like this, Tom.
Something must have happened
to him, let me call 911.
- [TOM] Wait, I'm
just gonna work my way
around the rest
of the foundations
just to be sure he
isn't hiding somewhere.
- Fine, don't take all night.
(rain pouring)
(wood creaking)
- So what became
of this reverend?
- He killed himself
here in the cabin,
but he knew that his soul
would never rest in peace.
- What are you saying, honey?
- I saw him down there.
- You saw him, you mean
you saw his remains?
(wood creaking)
(person growling)
- Noah.
(person shouting)
- That's it, I'm
calling the cops.
- For what I'm about to receive,
may the Lord make
me truly thankful.
(person shouting)
(person growling)
(object whirring)
- Shit, of all the stupid,
fucking ridiculous.
Why do I ever even
listen to you Tom?
Oh God, what am I
even doing here?
- I think dad's dead mom
and Noah too.
(tense music)
- This never should
have happened.
Oh God, we shouldn't
even be here.
Oh God, it's all my fault.
- How can it be your fault, mom?
We're only here
because dad moved out.
- He wanted to come back.
We talked about it on
the phone Thursday.
He said he wanted to give
it all up and come back.
- He said what?
- Thanksgiving always
just meant so much to him.
But I told him I was
just so mad with him.
I told him he'd made his bed,
but he was just so
excited to see you kids.
Now here we are.
- Look, it's simple.
If we're going to call for
help, we need to open the safe
and all we need in order to
do that is the combination.
Tom had it in his pocket.
- Are you suggesting
someone goes down there?
- Well, how hard can it be?
It's only a few meters
between here and the bedroom.
- How big is a meter?
- It's about, look,
it doesn't matter.
The point is, the combination
could be right
here in front of us
if we could just find Tom.
- Find Tom's body you mean.
- If that's the case well, yes.
- Go ahead then.
- Me?
- Why not, I don't see you
doing anything else useful.
- Have you seen
what I'm wearing?
I can't go crawling
around in tunnels.
- You could change your clothes.
- Cyndy, all of my
clothes look like this.
- I'll do it.
- No, don't be stupid.
If anyone is going to do
this, it's going to be me.
- Mom, no, no, no, no, no.
- It'll be okay.
Like Sara said, I just
have to go in far enough
to get the combination.
- But that man, that
thing is down there.
- And your father
wasn't ready for it.
But I will be.
If that thing comes near me,
I'm going to carve
myself a turkey.
(thunder crashing)
(wood creaking)
Come on you bastard,
just try me.
If you're real.
If you've killed my son.
(liquid pouring)
- What are you doing?
My mom is risking
her life down there.
- What do you want me to do?
Shout encouragement
through the floorboards?
(tense music)
(wood creaking)
(dramatic music)
Hurts does it?
Still, no more than you deserve.
Seems you found a way to
fuck up my weekend after all.
- What?
I didn't want any of this.
- Oh Christ, is there no
more booze in this place?
(door banging)
- [CYNDY] Andi.
- Mom.
- Can you get over to the vent?
- [CYNDY] Here, take this.
- Got it.
- Can you give that to Sara
so she can open the safe?
- I don't think I
should do that mom.
- Do what? What's that?
(tense music)
The combination to the safe.
Wonderful, well done.
- Can you get our cell
phones and call 911?
We need an ambulance for Andi
and the fire department
to dig me out of this maze
as fast as possible.
What are you doing?
- You can rot down
there for all I care.
And as for you.
(person screaming)
(flesh whirring)
- Leave her alone, you bitch.
- I'll leave her
alone all right,
just as soon as I
call myself a cab.
(rain pouring)
(tense music)
(machine beeping)
- What are we gonna do?
- Find my own way out of here.
(door whirring)
(person grunting)
I will be with you soon honey.
It's just a couple
of meters, right?
- Right.
- Is he down there, that thing?
- Don't worry about it.
(tense music)
(wood creaking)
(person growling)
Go away.
- Mom.
- [REVEREND FULLER] For
what I'm about to receive.
- I said go away.
- [REVEREND FULLER] May the
Lord make me truly thankful.
- Go away you
rotting sack of shit.
- Mom.
(object whirring)
Mom, mom!
- Did I miss something?
- Mom.
- Oh dear.
(person crying)
I'm sorry this weekend's been
a bit shit for you darling,
but looking on the bright side,
I think I've dodged
a bullet, don't you?
(thunder crashing)
(door whirring)
(person screaming)
(person shouting)
(object whirring)
- Mom.
(gentle music)
Mom, the cell phone.
(phone beeping)
- [Announcer] 911,
what's your emergency?
- It's complicated.
- [Announcer] Ma'am,
ma'am, are you still there?
(upbeat music)